# Nicole Dagnenica | Full Stack Web Developer

### **Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer and Designer with a passion for learning and developing my skills in the exciting environment of web development and design. I have experience in Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS and Photoshop and a background in product development for a major retailer. I have developed strong skills in design, communication, team-building and management that will make a positive impact on a company's profitability.

### **Projects**

Project Dashboard: Links to: Github Repo, Heroku App

A project management application which a business can use to create and track client projects.

- Created a Ruby web application using Ruby on Rails CRUD, MVC framework.
- · Implemented restful routing and nested routes.
- · Designed database schema and stored data using Sqlite and Active Record.
- · Added validations and flash error messages to prevent invalid data from being saved.
- Leveraged Bcrypt to secure user passwords and authenticate logins.
- · Used OmniAuth and Oauth authentication with Github.

# Project Dashboard with Javascript: Links to: Github repo, Heroku App This is an extension of Project Dashboard project.

Created an internal API and used AJAX to render an index, show and form submission.

#### Sleepy Star: Links to: Github Repo, Heroku App

A web application for a user to track a Baby's sleep schedule.

- · Created a Ruby web application using Sinatra CRUD, MVC framework.
- · Designed database schema and stored data using Sqlite and Active Record.
- Added validations and flash error messages to prevent invalid data from being saved.
- Leveraged Bcrypt to secure user passwords and authenticate logins.
- · Designed background image in Photoshop.

#### Book Review: Links to: Github Repo

Used Ruby to create a CLI application to view the top 50 books that all kids should read before they are 12 years old as provided and reviewed by Common Sense Media.

- · Used Nokogiri to scrape data from Common Sense Media.
- · Created objects using Ruby.

## **Employment**

# Macy's Merchandising Group, New York, NY (4/2004-9/2012)

Associate Project Manager, Ready-To-Wear Moderate & Alfani (1/1/11-9/1/2012)

• Supported the GVP in managing product development and buying calendars for major private brands.

#### Associate Product Manager, Ready-To-Wear Sweaters & Woven's (9/5/06-1/1/11)

- Development of new product from original design concept to in-store delivery.
- · Communicate, coordinate and liaison among design, color, technical and overseas offices.
- 2010 Product development responsibility for \$43M landed cost shipments.
- Brand Recognition Award 2009: recognized for exceeding margin results and sales plan by 7% with a 23% increase over prior year.

#### Associate Acount Manager, New Business Development (4/1/04-9/5/06)

- Account Manager of Private Label brands with Hudson Bay Company, generating sales volume of 16.7M with an increase of 20%.
- · Top Performer Award 2005: Award for exceeding shipment plan by 56%.

# Royal Chain Inc., New York, NY (1/2002-4/2004) Assistant Product Manager, Fine Jewelry

Specialized in the product development and sales of gold jewelry.

#### Contact

nnardella@gmail.com New York, NY (201) 874-6680 Portfolio Site Github Blog Linkedin

#### **Skills**

Ruby
Ruby on Rails
SQL
Sinatra
Javascript
JQuery
React
Redux
HTML / CSS

Responsive Design
Git / Github
Secure Password Authentication
Wireframing

Photoshop

### **Education**

Flatiron School (2018- 2019):

Online Software Engineering Program for developing web applications.

S.U.N.Y Empire State College (2018): Digital Art & Design:

Photoshop - GPA 4.0

#### Codecademy (2018):

Pro Intensive: Build Websites from Scratch: Certificate

# Johnson & Wales University, Providence, RI

- Bachelor of Science, Marketing, 2001
- Associates of Science, Computer Business Applications, 1999
- · Dean Lists Honors